<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<xml>
<records>
<record><source-app name="HighWire" version="7.x">Drupal-HighWire</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Therezan, Rodrigo</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Kortbeek, Ruy</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Vendemiatti, Eloisa</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Legarrea, Saioa</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">de Alencar, Severino M.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Schuurink, Robert</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Bleeker, Petra</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Peres, Lázaro E. P.</style></author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors></contributors><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Genetic factors outside the metabolic cluster for plastid-derived sesquiterpenes are required to pursue arthropod-resistant tomatoes</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">bioRxiv</style></secondary-title></titles><dates><year><style  face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2020</style></year><pub-dates><date><style  face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2020-01-01 00:00:00</style></date></pub-dates></dates><elocation-id><style  face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2020.02.21.960112</style></elocation-id><doi><style  face="normal" font="default" size="100%">10.1101/2020.02.21.960112</style></doi><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%"></style></volume><issue><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%"></style></issue><abstract><style  face="normal" font="default" size="100%">To deal with arthropod pests the tomato wild relatives produce a variety of defense compounds in their glandular trichomes. In Solanum habrochaites LA1777, a functional cluster of genes on chromosome 8 controls plastid-derived sesquiterpene synthesis not found in cultivated tomatoes. The main genes at the cluster are Z-prenyltransferase (zFPS) that produces Z-Z-farnesyl diphosphate (Z,Z-FPP), and Santalene and Bergamotene Synthase (SBS) that uses Z,Z-FPP to produce α-santalene, β-bergamotene, and α-bergamotene in type-VI glandular trichomes. Both LA1777 and cultivated tomatoes have type-VI trichomes, but the gland in cultivated tomato is much smaller containing low levels of monoterpenes and cytosolic-derived sesquiterpenes, which do not provide tomato with the same pest resistance as in LA1777. We successfully transferred the plastid-derived sesquiterpene pathway from LA1777 to type-VI trichomes of a cultivated tomato (cv. Micro-Tom, MT) by a back-crossing approach. The trichomes of the introgressed line named MT-Sesquiterpene synthase 2 (MT-Sst2) produced even higher levels of α-santalene, β-bergamotene, and α-bergamotene than the type-VI glandular trichomes of LA1777. We also noticed that the type-VI trichome internal storage-cavity size increases in MT-Sst2, probably as an “inflated balloon” effect of the increased amount of sesquiterpenes. Surprisingly, the presence of high amounts of plastid-derived sesquiterpenes was not sufficient to confer resistance to various tomato pests in MT-Sst2. Since MT-Sst2 made the same sesquiterpenes as LA1777, this points to additional factors, outside the genomic region thought to be the metabolic cluster, necessary to obtain arthropod-resistant tomatoes. Our results also provide a better understanding of the morphology of S. habrochaites type-VI trichomes.One-sentence summary Cultivated tomatoes harboring the plastid-derived sesquiterpenes from S. habrochaites need additional genetic components necessary to convert them into effective insecticides.</style></abstract></record>
<record><source-app name="HighWire" version="7.x">Drupal-HighWire</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Pailles, Yveline</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Awlia, Mariam</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Julkowska, Magdalena</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Passone, Luca</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Zemmouri, Khadija</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Negrão, Sónia</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Schmöckel, Sandra M.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Tester, Mark</style></author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors></contributors><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">A diversity of traits contributes to salinity tolerance of wild Galapagos tomatoes seedlings</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">bioRxiv</style></secondary-title></titles><dates><year><style  face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2019</style></year><pub-dates><date><style  face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2019-01-01 00:00:00</style></date></pub-dates></dates><elocation-id><style  face="normal" font="default" size="100%">642876</style></elocation-id><doi><style  face="normal" font="default" size="100%">10.1101/642876</style></doi><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%"></style></volume><issue><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%"></style></issue><abstract><style  face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Traits of modern crops have been heavily selected in agriculture, causing the commercial lines to be more susceptible to harsh conditions, which their wild relatives are naturally better able to withstand. Understanding the developed mechanisms of tolerance present in wild relatives can enhance crop performance under stress. In this study, salinity tolerance traits of two species of wild tomato endemic to the Galapagos Islands, Solanum cheesmaniae and Solanum galapagense, were investigated. Since these tomatoes grow well despite being constantly splashed with seawater, they could be a valuable genetic resource for improving salinity tolerance in commercial tomatoes. To explore their potential, over 20 traits reflecting plant growth, physiology and ion content were recorded in 67 accessions of S. cheesmaniae and S. galapagense and two commercial tomato lines of Solanum lycopersicum. Salt treatments of 200 mM NaCl were applied for ten days, using supported hydroponics. Great natural variation was evident in the responses of the Galapagos tomatoes to salt stress and they also displayed greater tolerance to salt stress than the commercial lines tested, based on multivariate trait analyses. Although Galapagos tomatoes in general exhibited better tolerance to salt stress than the commercial lines tested, the accessions LA0317, LA1449 and LA1403 showed particularly high salinity tolerance based on growth maintenance under stress. Thus, Galapagos tomatoes should be further explored using forward genetic studies to identify and investigate the genes underlying their high tolerance and be used as a resource for increasing salinity tolerance of commercial tomatoes. The generated data, along with useful analysis tools, have been packaged and made publicly available via an interactive online application (https://github.com/mmjulkowska/La_isla_de_tomato) to facilitate trait selection and the use of Galapagos tomatoes for the development of salt tolerant commercial tomatoes.</style></abstract></record>
<record><source-app name="HighWire" version="7.x">Drupal-HighWire</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Oluwatobi, Ayodele Samuel</style></author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors></contributors><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Physiological responses of two accessions of tomato to three distance regimes in juvenile oil palm-tomato intercrop in rainforest zone of nigeria</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">bioRxiv</style></secondary-title></titles><dates><year><style  face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2020</style></year><pub-dates><date><style  face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2020-01-01 00:00:00</style></date></pub-dates></dates><elocation-id><style  face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2020.05.31.126771</style></elocation-id><doi><style  face="normal" font="default" size="100%">10.1101/2020.05.31.126771</style></doi><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%"></style></volume><issue><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%"></style></issue><abstract><style  face="normal" font="default" size="100%">This study was conducted during the rainy season of 2017 within the alleys of juvenile oil palms that were 2-year-old at the oil palm plantation located in Ala, Akure-North Local Government, Ondo State. Tomato accessions (NGB 01665 and NG/AA/SEP/09/053) were intercropped at 1, 2 and 3 m from the juvenile oil palm within the alley in a randomized complete block design. The results showed that tomato (NGB 01665 and NG/AA/SEP/09/053) planted at 3 m from the juvenile oil palm performed better than those at other planting distances in terms of growth and yield attributes with number of fruit; fruit weight and yield per hectare of 39.50, 2265.8 g and 3.74 ton/ha respectively. However, the control (sole) recorded the best yield but was not significantly different from those planted at 3 m from the juvenile oil palm. Varietal advantage was recorded by tomato (NGB 01665) with higher number of fruits, fruit weight and yield per hectare (26.94, 1834 g and 3.158 ton/ha) respectively. Intercropping advantage was not recorded for any of the intercropping distance regimes during the trial (when the juvenile oil palms were 2-year-old), with LER values less than unity.Competing Interest StatementThe authors have declared no competing interest.</style></abstract></record>
<record><source-app name="HighWire" version="7.x">Drupal-HighWire</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Gupta, Prateek</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Dholaniya, Pankaj Singh</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Devulapalli, Sameera</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Tawari, Nilesh Ramesh</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Sreelakshmi, Yellamaraju</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Sharma, Rameshwar</style></author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors></contributors><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Reanalysis of Genome Sequences of tomato accessions and its wild relatives: Development of tomato genomic variation (TGV) database integrating SNPs and INDELs polymorphisms</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">bioRxiv</style></secondary-title></titles><dates><year><style  face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2020</style></year><pub-dates><date><style  face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2020-01-01 00:00:00</style></date></pub-dates></dates><elocation-id><style  face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2020.04.16.044495</style></elocation-id><doi><style  face="normal" font="default" size="100%">10.1101/2020.04.16.044495</style></doi><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%"></style></volume><issue><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%"></style></issue><abstract><style  face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Motivation Facilitated by technological advances and expeditious decrease in the sequencing costs, whole-genome sequencing (WGS) is increasingly implemented to uncover variations in cultivars/accessions of many crop plants. In tomato (Solanum lycopersicum), the availability of the genome sequence, followed by the resequencing of tomato cultivars and its wild relatives, has provided a prodigious resource for the improvement of traits. A high-quality genome resequencing of 84 tomato accessions and wild relatives generated a dataset that can be used as a resource to identify agronomically important alleles across the genome. Converting this dataset into a searchable database, including information about the influence of SNPs on protein function, provides valuable information about the genetic variations. The database will assist in searching for functional variants of a gene for introgression into tomato cultivars.Results A recent release of better-quality tomato genome reference assembly SL3.0, and new annotation ITAG3.2 of SL3.0, dropped 3,857 genes, added 4,900 novel genes, and updated 20,766 genes. Using the above version, we remapped the data from the tomato lines resequenced under the “100 Tomato Genome ReSequencing Project” on new tomato genome assembly SL3.0 and made an online searchable Tomato Genomic Variations (TGV) database. The TGV contains information about SNPs and InDels and expands it by functional annotation of variants with new ITAG3.2 using SIFT4G software. This database with search function assists in inferring the influence of SNPs on the function of a target gene. This database can be used for selecting SNPs, which can be potentially deployed for improving tomato traits.Availability and Implementation TGV is freely available at http://psd.uohyd.ac.in/tgv.Contact rameshwar.sharma{at}gmail.comCompeting Interest StatementThe authors have declared no competing interest.</style></abstract></record>
</records>
</xml>